William Merrow

3214 29th St. Apt 3, Astoria, NY 11106 – william.merrow@gmail.com – 603-568-0366 Portfolio: wmerrow.github.io/

Summary

Information designer with five years of experience creating static and interactive data visualizations on a range of public policy issues. Ability to approach projects from technical, creative, and project management standpoints. High attention to detail. Passion for clear and effective charts.

Skills

data visualization data analysis UX design responsive design user research usability testing project management

Tools

Adobe Illustrator Sketch R (ggplot2) Excel (VBA) Tableau HTML CSS D3.js

Education

Pratt Institute, M.S. in Data Analytics and Visualization expected 2021

Coursework in data visualization, data analysis, user experience, usability testing, programming

Tufts University, B.A. 2011, summa cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa

Major: International Relations, Minor: Sociology; coursework in statistics and econometrics

School for International Training, Cochabamba, Bolivia, January to May 2010

Professional Experience

Data Visualization Designer

Council on Foreign Relations, New York, NY November 2018 to present

- Design static and interactive data visualizations for editorial and research publications, working across teams to respond to requests and pitch ideas, creating effective charts and maps in keeping with organizational style guide
- Build interactive charts using D3.js and perform quality assurance on interactive web applications
- Manage data visualization projects and coordinate workload of graphics team to handle assignments simultaneously in a deadline-driven environment

Data Analyst & Visualization Specialist

Graphicacy, Washington, DC September 2015 to October 2018

- Lead design of web-based visualizations for major think tank and nonprofit clients, using Adobe Illustrator, Tableau, Excel, and R to create clear and compelling graphics, working with researchers to ensure visualization design clearly communicated results and accomplished intended goals
- Design websites, using Sketch to create high quality wireframes and comps in a deadline-based environment
- Lead data analysis projects, using R and Excel to manipulate and analyze large public datasets
- Manage large projects (\$100k+), managing developers and communicating with client to ensure project success
- Develop and lead workshops on data visualization best practices, create data visualization style guide, represent Graphicacy at conferences and events
- Contribute to business development and strategic planning, securing new clients and helping to grow business

Princeton in Latin America Fellow in Monitoring & Evaluation The DREAM Project, Cabarete, Dominican Republic August 2014 to August 2015

Independent coursework:

Intermediate D3 for Data Visualization, Knight Center

Data Visualization with D3, Knight Center

Sketch 3: Mobile and Web Designs, Udemy

Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

Language Skills:

Spanish - intermediate German - proficient

- Led redesign, migration, and adoption of Salesforce database, creating objects, workflows, reports, and dashboards, using Tableau to visualize student data
- Managed and analyzed student data to assess education programs, identifying trends and ensuring data quality
- Led basic to advanced Excel workshops for all staff; trained managers in use of Salesforce and Tableau
- Managed data and reporting for USAID grant, leading to perfect score on audit of data system

Special Assistant to the President & CEO

InterAction, Washington, DC August 2011 to August 2014

- Coordinated data and communications for \$1.5b food security pledge by 30 international NGOs; prepared data for use in remarks of President Obama and then-Secretary Clinton
- Authored remarks, blogs, and articles for CEO on range of international development topics; authored policy briefs, published in 2012 Reality of Aid report on the role of corporations in foreign aid; coordinated drafting, editing, and copyediting of 42 policy briefs for flagship publication
- Managed advocacy projects, analyzing legislative language and meeting with congressional staff; managed CEO-level taskforces on aid reform and corporations in international development
- Promoted to Senior Associate level (2012) and Coordinator level (2014); voted Best Team Player